

Maple Grove, MN 55369

□ 480.254.7080 | ■ ethanaa@gmail.com | ♠ www.ethanaa.com | ☑ lunias | 🖹 ethan-anderson | 🛅 ethanaa

# **Summary**

Highly skilled full-stack software professional with over 10 years experience who has a broad range of software development and information technology skills. Equally comfortable serving a role working on back-end (Java, Spring, Hibernate / JPA), integration (REST, SOAP, Kafka, RabbitMQ), or front-end (JavaScript, Vue.js, Node.js, HTML5). Also knowledgeable about creating domain models and designing database schemas using a variety of databases including MS SQL, Oracle, H2, MongoDB, and Elasticsearch. Well-versed in UNIX and used to working with a CLI.

Passionate continual learner who quickly adapts to new technologies and problem spaces. Strong problem solver who welcomes challenging tasks. Stand out history of meeting or exceeding timelines for customers with high quality deliverables. Excellent communicator, enjoyed by teammates for collaborative approach and positivity as well as expertise.

# **Skills Inventory**

- Developed a Google Assistant skill with Dialogflow and AWS Lambda.
- Designed and implemented a distributed Master Data Management solution using Apache Kafka and Elasticsearch.
- Built, tested, deployed, and integrated with a suite of authentication, authorization, and profile management web services for a Fortune 500
- Created new services for and upgraded current services within an enterprise integration layer comprised of REST and SOAP based services at a leading online university.
- Leverages Spring Boot expertise to implement rapid prototypes.
- Developed a RESTful API to interface with an existing telecommunications scheduling platform using Java and Spring.
- Used AngularJS and Vue.js to create modern web-based administrative applications. Delivered Java clients for various video conferencing APIs using SOAP, REST, and XML-RPC.
- Built a video conferencing endpoint management console application using ExtJS. Experienced with Test Driven Development (TDD) using JUnit.
- Interfaced with users to deliver code optimizations on-site at an active mining operation.
- Automated repetitive tasks such as refactoring code, updating databases, managing servers using Bash/Python scripts Comfortable working in a command line environment.
- Excellent debugging, troubleshooting and problem solving skills.
- Experienced in Agile software development.

# Work Experience\_

Vivial Bloomington, MN SOFTWARE ENGINEER Anr 2019 - Present

• Currently getting a lot of hands on experience with AWS.

- · Migrated a legacy Python Django application running on EC2 to Convox and subsequently maintained it; involving RabbitMQ, MongoDB, and
- Designed and implemented a nightly, continuous ETL task in Node.js with Convox for exporting data from MongoDB to RDS (PostgreSQL).
- Created a pixel tracking service and scripted migration of legacy tracking data to the new system.

**Solution Design Group** Golden Valley, MN

CONSULTANT Jan. 2015 - Apr. 2019

· Honed skills as an enterprise Java Software Engineer through multiple opportunities to work with excellent clients.

**Best Buy / SDG** Richfield, MN

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Developed a Google Assistant skill with DialogFlow and deployed to production on AWS Lambda.
- Put together a logging framework and Kibana dashboard for tracking user metrics.
- Created a prototype tech support chatbot using Python and Rasa.
- Led the initiative to better understand modern NLU / NLP techniques and developed a prototype classification engine in Java using Word2Vec and LIBSVM.

## Be The Match: The National Marrow Donor Program / SDG

Minneapolis, MN

Nov. 2018 - Apr. 2019

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jul. 2018 - Nov. 2018

Jan. 2017 - Jul. 2018

- Worked on retirement of legacy Java EE software solutions.
- · Refactored existing Java codebase to allow for a dramatic reduction in time required to implement new message handling logic.

TCF Bank / SDG Plymouth, MN

- SOFTWARE ENGINEER • Helped to build a Master Data Management platform to contain 4 million plus customers.
- Leveraged Kafka and Kafka Streams to provide a system capable of realtime data processing.
- Used Elasticsearch and Vue.js to create an interface for finding and maintaining customer data.

AUGUST 10, 2020 ETHAN ANDERSON · RÉSUMÉ Cargill / SDG Plymouth, MN

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Jul. 2016 - Jan. 2017

- Wrote RESTful services in Python to provide a custom API for SunGard's Front Arena.
- Developed a reconciliation service with Spring Boot and Spring Batch to aid in the validation of our integration efforts.

#### **Target Corporation / SDG**

Minneapolis, MN

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Jul. 2015 - Jul. 2016

- Built various microservices for authentication, authorization, and profile management using Spring Boot and Apache Camel.
- · Created numerous Spring Boot Starters to reduce the configuration overhead of new projects.
- · Wrote Chef cookbooks to automate configuration of OpenStack nodes.
- · Utilized Dropwizard Metrics and Grafana to build a dashboard for visualizing application performance.

# Capella University / SDG

Minneapolis, MN

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jan. 2015 - Jul. 2015

- Developed new services and enhanced current services using both SOAP and RESTful web services for the core enterprise integration layer.
- · Created automatic asynchronous assessment scoring logic for institution's readiness center product. • Leveraged Twitter Bootstrap and built a rapid prototype that utilized JHipster.
- Documented and conducted knowledge transfer sessions.

#### Renovo Software Inc. / Global Tel Link

Minneapolis, MN

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Aug. 2012 - Dec. 2014

- Performed software enhancements to a Java, web-based video scheduler product.
- Designed and implemented a RESTful API for Video Scheduler using Spring Framework.
- Integrated core software with third party video conferencing APIs (SOAP, REST, XML-RPC).
- · Built an endpoint manager web application using Spring Framework and Ext JS.
- Implemented a Video Scheduler Admin Tool as a single page application in AngularJS utilizing a RESTful API.

## Jigsaw Inc./ Leica Geosystems Mining

Tucson, AZ

PROJECT ENGINEER

Sep. 2010 - Aug. 2012

- · Provided customized software support and enhancements to company clients on a daily basis in the form of code updates to our software
- · Rapidly developed, tested, and deployed code on site using immediate customer input to expedite the installation and configuration of the
- Utilized PostgreSQL databases and queries to pull and display data inside of customized views of our MineOPS application.

# Education

### U of A (University of Arizona)

Tucson, AZ

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND MINOR IN JAPANESE

2006 - 2010

· Courses of note: Computational Linguistics, Operating Systems, Algorithms, Finite State Automata, Game Design.